Maybe they are coming
back together with
their family for
Thanksgiving Day.
Weekend star.
Mm-hm.
Okay, So we can start
our class things.
I will record in.
So good afternoon
everyone.
This is our
course, our face.
A five through
eight are the ones,
the computer
architecture and
the University
of New Mexico.
So yeah.
Yes, way to reduce
during the first
two classes,
you can still
remember that we
have got the computer
architecture right.
Including, thank you.
Including the design from
the hardware to
software as well.
That optimizations
so that the span of
the computer
architecture has
the main some
penitentiaries
that yeah, that's good.
Thank you.
So compare our teacher
is concern that with
the balancing of
the performance,
efficiency and also
the parsed Gaza roll
up and a right of the
computer or the system.
So for one of the
most important,
say it that the instruction
set architecture
can be used to illustrate
the balance between
these competing factors
among the performance,
efficiency, cost, and
also reliability.
So, and we'll
talk more about
the instruction set
architecture and
a more complex a
structure that none of
the enabled programmers to
know to run more space
efficient programs.
Or there are
single instruction
that can cause some
higher level abstraction,
such like the, the,
the architecture about
the X86 move instruction
a computer system.
However, there
are some, yeah,
yeah, benefits and
disadvantages of this.
So based on the design of
the computer
architecture at J way,
No, including
the instruction
set architecture,
the memory hierarchy.
So as we know, there are
some techniques
from yet they are
designed to overcome
the limitations
are on performance
in the past
might write that out.
Also. They can use it to
boost up the system
performance.
For instance, ethnicity.
Here we know the
mottos likes
the instruction
level parallelism
that they had ever
paradise them.
And also the trend,
our paradigms them.
Yeah, Daddy, better to
overcome the
limitation from
the instruction level
parallelism ad they
can further improve
the performance.
So, yeah, Actually,
sir, this picture,
gang as was shown
before, the front,
the physical hardware to
the software applications.
We have ones
through the layers
across a computer
architecture design.
And we already know
that the die and
the optimization
for the.com,
they design a
computing system.
Or we can say that for
the general computing
systems, right?
So today we are going
to a new lecture
that we're going to none
the train up
some customized,
all emerging
computing decide
as what the optimization
for that our teachers,
in addition to the
general architecture
of the way talked
to before.
So yeah, that is one
of the training about
the future of computing.
That is the heterogeneous
architecture
as we talked before.
So this cannot von
teachers and
also, you know,
da, da, da, da cans
off the computing
components
on the heterogeneous
architecture.
A degree like the CPUs,
GPUs or DSP,
including ours us,
FPGAs and also
applications
computing compounds as we
call it data ethics.
Son.
Hey, one short video
to show the fusion
of the computer is better
for the heterogeneous
architecture,
including death panels
computing components here.
So our showed the video
here to
show now heterogeneous
computing system.
Good.
Are there anyway, we can
continue that since
you're going to
watch a video after
class if you like. Okay.
So obey.
So this will be a short
video to show you
that the about the future
of computing that,
especially for the
heterogeneous oxygen
with the CPU GPU, DSP,
FPGA as well, the A6,
as we've shown before,
that as a basic
computing components
in the end.
Yeah, That is not
the general design
of the computer
architecture.
That is the specific
computing architecture
does that
with the kind of
this components.
Sum, yeah, as an
overview, here,
there are two main
directions of
the development of the
computing lab teacher.
So focused on what the
first way is to define
the application-specific
computing architectures.
For example, there
are adequately
specific instruction
set processor.
We caught a stick and also
the FPGA field
programmable gate array.
That is one popular
that you might have
for me, no waste.
And also another one about
the application-specific
integrated circuits.
That is a wall, we call
it the stick here.
So come panelists,
that general-purpose
processor,
traditional DSP GPU CPU
and base these diners.
All, this gives
the eyes are
dedicated for that
specific applications.
For like two
full flow flow.
Usually they are designing
for satisfying the image,
all the performance or
the power requirement,
or even other
requirements on the,
uh, from the
application side.
So they fought the
application specific.
So another way
for computing
architecture design is to
explore the hatred years,
medical powerful legs,
the domain-specific
computing architecture,
right?
That is the one
another ways to
the computer architecture
design in order to
explore the heterogeneous
model could not vote.
So in the following,
we will introduce
this handoff computing
aggregator design
with more details here.
So yeah,
in the very beginning of
the architecture
design will let you
know that these ions,
the general purpose
processor first,
that is GPP as
we're shown here.
So the general
purpose processors
they add is Dion of four,
has a name shown here.
For the general-purpose
computers,
such as the
personal computers,
all some of the
workstations.
So the computation speed
of a general
purpose processor,
thus paid as the
main concern.
And the cost of the
general-purpose processor
SU been much higher
than that of the legs.
That's a DSPS or the
microcontrollers.
So all the techniques that
can increase
the CPU speed,
how they apply to
the general
purpose processors
in research design.
So on the other hand,
the general growers
processors aren't always
the Haganah
processors that
Connolly first
come to the man.
Anyone can write the
computer program, right?
What a general
purpose processor.
So the general
reverse processors,
the processors
dot, you know,
the power desktop
computers.
And they are at
the center of the
computer revolution.
You almost that
began in the 1970s.
So they have a
lung Historia
more than 40 years.
Though.
The landscape of the
microprocessor cheese
that is dotted with
large long barrel
of the devices from note
the variety of the
manufacturers.
So this different
processors,
while are unique in
their own right.
Yeah, they can share
some similarly
similarities.
Or we call it the
January instruction set,
or instructions
sequencer and memory
management unit,
MMU, or they
share resources
between this general
purpose processors.
So there are basically
two general types of
the instructions that
in this processor.
The first one, at
that the machines are
waste found a broad
instruction sets,
also known as
the complex instruction
set computers,
as we've shown before,
that is fakes.
And then Nazareth
that the machines was
the narrow instruction
says, Yeah, we are.
With that risk right now,
reduced instruction
set computers.
So generally lacks
us this instructions
if the assembly program
or higher for
instructions.
And they can be
used to dress
the efficient implementation
of the window,
the certain
software functions.
So on the other hand,
as we showed before,
the race instructions
that yeah,
they are narrow, right?
And they add these
dye to produce
the efficient quote
from the compliers.
So the difference between
the states get raised.
Yeah, arbitrary.
And both styles
of this too.
Designs right? Of
the processor.
They are converting into
a single hive off
the instruction set
actually still relies on
the weather at the mercy
of essays for all n,
If the race, they
both share a gener.
General the nature of
their instructions here.
So this includes
the instruction
that can perform
multiplications, addition,
or the storage about
this instruction
set or not,
tolerate your particular
type of applications.
So in the context of that,
yeah, da, da, da,
of the design of
this architecture is
actually the FPGA,
which the way I was
the interest or
the singular processing to
use this processors here.
So there is as
an aspect of
the general purpose
processor that is,
the use of the MMU,
that is a memory
management unit.
Immerse you in a
general-purpose processor.
Yeah, they are
designed for
the January applications,
as we said.
So they are, you're
going to carpet
with an operating system.
So this operating
system creates
a level of the abstraction
over the hardware.
They know the, the bad
applications with
little or no knowledge
of the underlying
hardware.
So this is they'll go
because the higher level
developer, though,
the lower-level
hardware, so they can do
some design that without
knowing author says
about the hardware.
So though thou will
be flexible for
the high level design.
So the program to be
wrong and necessary data,
they shouldn't be made
available at the
main memory.
So there is the general
data past that.
This half will consist
ALU and the EU,
but are large
register file.
So there are
multiple levels
of cache in order
to reduce the
memory latency
in the general-purpose
processor.
So again, the management
of the memory dies,
the tenors I, error
prone process,
an EHR system around a
lot more applications.
Actually, the
memory management
include the paging memory.
Distributed programming
at the data storage
is true are the different
blocks of memory.
So MM, you the
manual memory
management unit or
knows that developed to
say continuous center
of the mammary.
Make it easier for
the narrow axis.
Even though the, you know,
the underlying
memory structure
maybe framing
sternum and zeta or
they're too
difficult to control
some other fashion max,
multitasking system.
Yeah, in that situation,
there have been learning
content container stay for
an extended period after
temp right now I'm not
worthy or its contents.
So even the general
nature of the application
that it can be wrong on
the general-purpose
processor here,
actually, a memory
management unit is
control in any credible
in the control because
it allows the ISTE.
Blending up the different
applications with
no special care needed
on the evap are
part not means
that the vehicle
will be much
easier to handle
their part of
the work without
knowing others during
the Archaic turkeys,
I so the general
purpose processors
have the maximum
flexibility.
Yeah, As we
mentioned, some
of them about that.
Diners, all the
developers, right?
They are programmable,
supports
several high level
languages and they
can be used for any
general applications.
So compared with other
specific processors,
actually,
the general-purpose
processor shown here,
they have the short
time to market.
That means it will
cost are not always
the shortest latency to
be re to the market.
So they also have
the low nonrecurring
engineering
about the cost.
However, yet your brain,
they cost high
power consumption.
Of course they are not.
Frequently designed for
applications with that,
yeah, always the
best performance
or the power cost to here.
So yeah,
under contour of
the general progress
processors,
yeah, there are
application
specific architectures.
So one can of
the EBP specific
architecture
design as though,
as we've shown
that application
specific instructions
that the processor,
that a stick some
adaptations to
specific instruction
set processor end
is the macro
processor that
care to benefit us
the best-fit
application for
a domain of the
applications
or a domain of
the operations.
Focused on more
for the sum
of the processors.
Specific design for
the signal processing,
for the image processing,
or even for the
veil processing.
I'll either for the
digital communication.
So they are specific for
the applications
or the domain
of the upper operations.
So the
advocacy specific
instruction set processor
that is a component.
Are you going to use
the English system on
chip design and the
instruction set
of a state that is,
tell it to benefit a
specific application.
All right, so this
specialization wrote
the core or the processor
design actually
can provide a trade-off
between the flexibility of
a general-purpose
computing system
and the performance
of a mistake,
as we will show it later.
So for the
instruction set out,
the AC, it is
customized for the type
of the computation.
This computations I in
both NAS specific
application.
Yeah, so big, that
amazed thumb.
A steps have
a configurable a
structure instead.
So you overlay this course
are divided
into two parts.
And two parts
including the US
that in your logic
which can give
Phi minimum instruction
set our picture.
And the configurable
logic for this part.
They can be used to design
a new instructions so that
our two part about the
study design or the
Configure are configurable
logic design.
So they'll come
finger or logic can
be programmed either
in the field,
seminar fashion
to the FPGA
or theories or
chips synthesis.
So in additional with
the part about the
standard logical design.
So advocacy is best
if an instruction
set processor,
they have flexibility for
the requirements for
legacy application
with high performance.
The no power
consumption as we're at
the smaller silicon
at his dying cost.
So they can be used
as outer layer of
the hardware
accelerators for
the baseband
signal processing
or for the application
is like the polio coding.
So the traditional
hardware accelerators
for this
application action,
they suffer from
the dot, dot,
dot less or the lab
of the flexibility.
So it is very difficult to
reuse the hardware
data passed with
a handwritten Alexa
finite state machines,
right?
So again,
the compiler some of
the steps, actually,
they can help the
designer to update
the program or they can
reuse that data pass.
So typically,
now a step Giza
is more or less
dependent on the flow
because the
designing of such
cannot process
or from scratch
can be very complicated.
They have some basis to,
to, to, to river.
So there are
some, you know,
the commercial tools
to design the A6,
for example, or
the processor designer
from synopsis.
And there is an open
source too as well that
cause the TDA paste
that code is that
empowerment.
You can use that to decide
the instruction said.
The application specific
instruction set processor.
So this add some touristy.
Okay, Yesterday's I
saw another hand.
Yeah, In addition
to that, Issac,
there's another kind of
application specific
outpace your design.
Now we're caught
the digital
signal processor.
I'm sure you off
or we know with
our body days, DSP, right?
So digital
signal processor
is a step design
for that repetitive
multiply,
accumulate operation and
also be the reversal
of dressing the
best fit for
them for base panel
of operations.
So this dosing
and processing
as a specialized
microprocessor chip.
Yeah, they are with
their architecture
optimized for
dot operator needs of the,
specifically for
the digital signal
processing.
So DSPs.
February paid on
the most integrated
circuit chips.
And they are widely used
in the audio
signal processing.
The tenant communication,
digital image processing,
radar, Astana,
and also the
Alexa speech
recognition systems,
an income or consumer
electronic devices such
as mobile phones,
the disk drives,
and also lag for
the high definition
television
products nowadays,
we know as HD TV products.
So not go all the causes
for the DSP Design.
They are you but i
2, mayor of theatre,
or compressed
or containers
or grill would
analog signals.
So most general-purpose
microprocessors ads
were shown before.
They can also execute
that digital signal
processing algorithms
successfully.
But the general
purpose processors may
not be able to keep up
with the such processing,
continuous it
in real time.
So as a shy it for
the general purpose
process and when
they are facing
the digital signal
processing.
So although the
dedicated DSPS
you but I have better
power efficiency,
therefore, they
are more suitable
in the portable devices
such as mobile phones.
Because you are though
about power consumption,
concentrates
on that, that,
that, that we
need to consider.
Them are about
devices, right?
So DSPs often use
a spatial memory
architectures
data base map
out t-shirts.
Are you able to fetch
multiple data
fitting model
instruction at
the same time?
So 4x1?
Yes, piece of yeah,
also implemented
the data compression
technology
with the credit
cosine transform,
nowadays the DCT
transformation, right?
In particular, it
being widely used
a compression
technology, DSPs.
So digital signal
processors can also handle
the build time
processing to compute,
compute, it's better for
the computation
intensive tasks.
They can minimize
the cost of
two and also minimize
the power consumption.
Minimize optimize
the spatialized
that data has,
the instructions that you.
So DSPs can't, or
those that fought
the repetitive
numeric calculations.
Also for the high
memory bandwidth,
streaming data processing
with less
development time.
So far this can
of applications,
all the computations in
this APA patients were
introduce actuate DSB can
perform much better than
other architectures.
A special word for author,
including the
general robots,
microprocessors,
or other
application-specific
processor design.
So, yeah, Also
when we talk
about the professors,
you know,
we need to talk
about a game about
the Graphic
Processing Unit
that the GPUs were
introduced to before.
You're actually in
lecture five, right?
Yeah, let's reveal
the discussion
about the GPU here again,
gadgets to graphic
processing units,
specialized.
Yeah.
So as we're introduced
to before, yeah,
that electronic
circuit designed to
rapidly manipulate
and also
after the ban richer,
accelerate the creation
of the immediates right?
In a frame buffer in your
intended for the output to
display on the
device, right?
So the GPUs are
used in the legs.
The imbalances
sense awesome.
Mobile phones,
personal computers,
workstations,
as well as some
pin consumers.
So more than GPOs,
They efficient
at manipulating
computer graphics.
And also they
are efficient to
deal with the
inmates processing.
So they have the high
powered on rupture.
Actually, they can make
this GPUs more
efficient than
the general-purpose
central processing
unit or CPU.
That's why they
have efficiency.
At then the general
stay appeals
for the legs.
The operations are about
the algorithm that
processes the large
blocks of the data.
Especially data can be DO
that executed in parallel.
So in your
personal computer,
actual GPU can be present.
Baidu car, or they
can be imbedded on
a motherboard for Basil
with SAP us, We're
show people.
A certain CPUs, they
are imbedded on the
CPU die, right?
So GPOs can provide
the parallel computing by
massively data parallel
stream processing.
And they can also use
southern das thread.
Implementation
is like the hundreds
off the course.
So due to the cost
efficient and E is
the implementation of
the GPU and the
low latency and
also in those shapes
using the hardware
platform, right?
You is becoming
increasingly common to
use the general-purpose
graphics processing units.
Yeah, uh, together with
a CPU that we call
the GPGPU, right?
They used to as
the modified form of
the sperm processor,
or are we caught the matzo
processor as one of
the variations for the
SIMD architecture.
And they can run computer
Kernig's, right.
So this, the
term, you know,
the massive
computational power
of the mode of
graphics accelerators
share that
the pipeline does
a general-purpose
computing power.
Yeah, as opposed to
being the heart of
what azole to do
the graphical
operations, right?
So a certain
applications, yeah,
this application
repair that
there should be master
vector operations.
So this can, yeah,
the several orders of
magnitude higher
performance now,
conventional CPU.
So the two largest
discredited GPO designers,
you know, you are familiar
with AMD and NVIDIA.
So they nest to GPO
designers actually,
they are beginning
to pursue
that approach with
the array of the
occupations.
So both a Veda and
AMD have the
research team or
the pronoun two teams with
the staffer university
to create a GPO base,
a client, especially for
the affording home
distributed
computing project.
Like for the protein
folding calculation,
like this or odd
that data intensive
operations.
So they are focused on to
design that GPIOs follow
such kind of application
or stress can
off projects.
So what's below
for the legs?
For the, yeah, FPGAs
actually, yeah,
there's other
field programmable
gate array for
the seminar.
Use, your nerve.
These are actually the
researcher for that.
Yeah, Hey, was
at Hong Kong at
that time and talk
more about the design
of the FPGA
that there does
die optimization for
the FPGA system.
So actually for FPGA
that a degree
it is so cute.
It is decided to be
configured by our consumer
or can be configured
biodesign or after
manufacturing.
They're full.
The term field
programmable.
Yeah. Well, I
mean, you can
configured after
the manufacturing.
So the FPGA configuration,
it's generally
best specified
using hardware
description language,
basic flow as the HDL.
So in a seminar
to die used
for application-specific
integrated circuit,
that is the seminar
with the ACLU decide.
So the Thurber at the
elbow Ramsey predators,
they use it to specify
the configuration
of a PGA.
But there's this increase
in a real, you know,
due to the advent of
the electronic design
automation to us today.
So I said the core
architecture for the GPS,
the coarctation
contains an area of
the programmable
logic blocks and
a heirarchy of
the reconfigurable
interconnects.
Not dancing to connote,
can know the blocks
to be well together.
And luckily, many logical
gates that can be
into world in different
configurations.
So the logical blocks
can be configured to
perform complex
combination functions.
They are mallocing
logic gates,
legs, and an XOR.
So a most FPGA eddy size
actually the
logical blocks.
They also include
the memory elements.
And these elements maybe
simple flip-flops or
more content
blocks of memory.
So many, many FPGA,
these eyes can be
re-programmed
to implement different
logic functions.
Or no, the flexible,
real, comfortable,
wearable computing as
performed either
computer software.
So in traditional mode,
this flexibility for
the FPGA design actually.
Fpga architectures
also have the memories
and also specialized
input and output blocks.
So more than FPGA as you
have read the DSP blocks,
also the hardware,
IP cores and stuff,
the workhorse.
All of this can enable
more and more
functionalities for
the application
that can be
run on the FPGA
architecture.
So the FPGA also have
a remarkable
embedded system
development due to that,
although the comparability
that they can start
the system software
development
simultaneously with
the 100 we're right.
And eight again, enabled
the system performance
simulation
and are very early phase
of the development.
And also the FPGA.
These are, although the
various system a petition,
self-aware and
hardware way right?
And their tours add
iterations before
the final phrasings.
A system architecture now
have more and more flex,
but in the design of the,
about the hardware,
software,
a different status.
Wisdom according to
the demands far
the applications.
So that is about the
reconfigurability
or two bands or with
a capability of the yeah,
we can say that the
flexibility for that ESI.
So after we know
the FPGAs and also the
DSP to here, right?
So one way need
to compare with
the aphasia is a
DSP processors.
We can find that
both of the FPGAs,
DSPs can offer
flexibility for rage,
huge add
programmability, right?
So specifically, digital
signal processing.
And it underpins modem,
wireless or as where
the wildlife, Camila,
patient's medical
or down obviously
equipment,
mandatory systems, audio
and video equipment.
And also that the
communists as
our products are
becoming increasingly
common in the
consumer's lives.
So due to the advances
in the semiconductor
technology,
10 even more complex
DSP algorithm,
the proton course, and
also the applications
are no feasible.
Yeah, this will
in turn increase
the complexity
of the system
and their products design.
So as the complex,
actually,
the complexity increases
about the DSPD side.
The system
reliability is no
longer solenoid divided
by the hardware
powerful and we're up at
a typical day in
a quantified a
meantime between
the funeral like some
me time to failure
we introduced
before the conclusion or
the mom and for
the architecture
design, right?
The system or not,
but it is increasingly
determined by the
hardware EPA,
software architectures
together.
So the ASO, they
are related to the
development and
a verification processes
and also the level
of the thigh.
Maintainability.
So all of these
are considered
together to
measure the dot,
the dot, the dot
reliability or
the performance
about the
character design.
So there is one
fundamental
architecture issue
that is about the pipe
of the hardware platform.
So DSB functions are
commonly implemented on
two types of the
programmable pamphlets,
including the
additional system,
digital signal processor,
and the Programmable
Gate Array that
Arthur ESPN at
PGI, FPGAs, right?
Dsps are specialized form
of the micro professor.
Well, and FPGAs, a form of
the highly
configurable hardware.
Actually, the part
that the use of
the DSPS was
nearly ubiquitous.
Waterways the need of
the many applications
that are
disturbing in
the processing
comorbidity of the DSPs.
Actually, the use of
a teacher is
growing rapidly,
especially in the
recent right.
So parented the, you know,
the primary
reason that most
engineers choose,
you choose to
use the FPGA,
all the DSP that
is driven by
the applications and
MITS requirement.
Therefore, the comparison
between the DSPs and
FPGAs actually focus on
the IPS cooperation.
So this will
certainly important.
This is not
the only other
bondage of the FPGA.
So it equally important
and often overlooked.
Actually, that is
the FPGAs inherent
advantage
in that they have
the other one is in
the product
that reliability and
maintainability tube.
Thus than or
DSP processors
has an advantage in
the time to market.
That means it is a
foster to be produced.
Well, they can
only support
those sequential
operations for
the applications
where the gender or
the FPGA kind of enable
the food in
parallel design.
And that FPGAs care of
the greater improvement
on the implementation
performance.
But the other one
for the FPGA,
that the cost is relatively
high and eight is
the most power consuming
than the DSP's.
So near the orange neuron,
project managers
can readily
killed the data of
their next product,
self-aware of it,
including FPGA,
DSP of answers, or they
can really use
this dot product.
So and most
technology com case,
there is you open a
law in town east of
the software bots
or problem report
along with the thumb
forward nice data will
contain the associated
and patches
or fixes, right?
So it has come to
be expected that
or structure we're
including the DSP code.
Now we are a content
some levels off
the box that the
best one can do.
That is to minimize
this box right before
they're ready.
So by comparision,
actually
during this stage, FPGA,
these dyes, they tended to
be updated and much
less frequently.
And it is January,
unusual event for
a manufacturer to
issue a feel an upgrade of
the FPGA configuration
file because it
takes time and age,
much a complex.
That's why the DSPS
has a shorter time to
market that the FPGAs,
this process or take
longer for the FPGA.
So in order to
Coke cans of
dog applications
with a distinct
performance demands.
Yeah, it is that merging
trained to decide
the heterogeneous
prototyping platforms.
Next, platforms can be
integrated with DSP.
Yeah, Actually
both DSPs and
FPGA components in order
to benefit from
their advantages
for the specific
applications.
Right?
After talking
about this can
of our teachers have,
for the, on the
other hand,
SQL mentioned several
times about that
application-specific
integrated circuits here.
Yeah, ethics.
They are also
raised as one
of the emerging
computing path thoughts
to actually the ethics
can provide the
customize the tail,
the hardware
solutions for that.
Yeah,
especially for those
specific application
or the platforms.
So application-specific
integrated circuit
that is in greedy
search your chip.
This tube is customized
for a particular use,
AC rather than the
intended for the
general purposes.
For example, achieved,
decide to run
a digital voice
recorder or
for high efficient
repeatable manner.
That is that Isaac,
an application specific
manner products nozzle,
what we call a SSB chips.
They intermediate
between the A6
and the industry
standard bridges.
So could legs
products about
the seven for their
road stereos.
And the A6 chips are
typically fabricated
using the,
the metal oxide
semiconductor
that is the most
technology.
So as the most
integrated into
the so-called chip
to start the A6,
accurate, they are
not reconfigurable.
Based is different from
dot dot data,
the FPGA, right?
Because FPGA is a
reconfigurable,
but a stick is not
reconfigurable and
they cannot be
upgraded after
manufacturing A6,
Their have monger design
and development
time before
computed to be
in the market
even than the FPGA.
So as before, FPGAs, yeah,
They are the modern
day technology for
building rapport
or prototype font,
the standard ports
right about there,
programmable
logic blocks and
a programmable
income connector.
Below them, FPGA to be
used in many different
applications.
Good, they had us
batting apart and
also the flexible part
for the designers to
be to be designed
with flexibility,
or it is reconfigurable
right foot
in many different
applications.
For the smaller
the size or
the lower production
runners at
a FPGA is maybe more
cost effective than them.
Is a design, even
the production.
So the nonrecurring
engineering cost for
the state can run into
the millions of dollars
to it is a very high cost.
So therefore, the
device manufacturers
typically prefer
the FPGA either
for the prototype and
also for the devices with
low production
balloon at ethics
for very large
production Vernon.
Well, you know the
long recruiting
engineering can
be on the rise
across many devices.
So specify what the A6,
they are either
designed by
the gate areas or
designer by the standard
cells as shown here.
So basically, the
gate areas you can
provide the
means by which a
large portion of
the general-purpose
new logic,
they can be used
as a Muslim
not elect to
access systems.
And they can be combined
into a single package,
your solution.
So both those
that are still in
the gate area
approaches on the A6,
they can reduce or
designers laid
out walk by,
unloading it onto
the computer
again to far east as
a good area in
the basic design
approach to design ad.
They can edit, can
manufacturer of
the application
specific integrated
circuit by
using a prefabricated
chip with components.
These components are later
interconnected
into the launch.
But devices, for example,
this devices can be a
NAND gates, flip flops.
Yeah, as better
according to
a pastor order by
any metal interconnect
layers in the factory.
So that means we may,
can be designed,
is dedicated to form
the demands of
the applications
or the customer.
So it is Seminar.
Yeah, it has the
similar technologies
to have also
being employed.
Design or two
manufacturers,
the analog and analog,
digital and
structure Arish.
But in general, these
are not caught,
they'll get
areas in the A6.
So a no
semiconductor design
and showed us
that are still
methodology that
mattered of
these tiny
application-specific
integrated circuits.
It special wisdom most on
a page to a lot
of pictures.
So standard methodology as
an example of
design, obstruction.
Obstruction.
A low level and are
very large scale
integration.
Now we call it
the VLR is right.
Hi, there. I
suddenly hour is
encapsulated into
abstract logic
representations,
satyagraha
navigate and does
cell-based a
methodology, right?
So the general class to
waste status,
they'll belongs.
So this will make
it possible for
one designer to focus
on the high level,
a focus on more of a
logical function, right?
For the high level
aspect of the design?
Well, another
designer during
the process can focus
on the implementation
aspects
for wisdom or the
feasible design.
So along with
the semiconductor
manufacturing,
advances are actuated that
does than or does their
methodology and has
helped other designers
scale ethics
from the
comparative simple,
single function ICE.
Integrated security side.
Yeah, comparator with
data complex modeling,
meaning gates, system
on chip design devices.
So these are
the gate arrays
and best banner
sales in the isaac
decide to provide
different functionality
or have the different
aspect for these IE,
the A6 for the
applications.
After we know the S6,
also the FPGAs, right?
So when we generate
that FPGAs and the
A6 here, yeah,
we can say that both of
the FPGAs and the basics,
they can hide a
parallel task is
to provide the greater
performance, right?
So massively thought that
FPGA style maize field
programmable gate,
again, can be
filled program
to work as per the
intended design.
That means it can work as
the microprocessor
or graphics card.
As both at once.
So that these diner
rolling an FPGA,
they are generally
created using
the hardware description
language such as
a VHDL or Verilog.
So FPGAs is made
up of a number
of the numbers of
the configurable
logic blocks
we call those TLBs, right?
And these blobs
are connected
waste or you know,
the programmable
interconnects.
Therefore, FPGAs and
our reconfigurable with
this components and
the interconnects
with shorter time.
And the considerable
logical blocks
are primarily made by
the lookup tables in
a multiplex here
as our flip-flops,
they can implement a
complex logic functions.
So apart from the
dark container
or logical blocks, the
ruling interconnect,
many FPGAs also
contain that
dedicated hard
authentic and blocks
for the various functions,
such as a block grant
or the DSP blocks,
and eternal external
memory controller
and such care of
components here.
So this component,
dedicated hardware blocks.
They are critical in
the campaign with the A6.
So for the A6 here,
compare with the FPGAs,
actually a six, we
know that they need
application-specific
integrated circuit,
right?
So it is a device that is
created just for a
specific purpose
of the function on arity.
So they contain
only one function
or an editor in there.
And through the left
tunnel for cheap,
they are not a
reconfigurable.
So I can perform only
guard function with
the higher clock
frequency, higher speed.
But their development is
much more expensive
and not flexible.
Compare with
FPGA especially.
So for example, the
CPUs in your phone.
Nowadays that AC, enemies
to the function as SAP or
voice who live, right?
It's logical function
can now be changed.
All cannot be reconfigured
to anything else
because it's
digital secured,
is made up of
the permanent connected
gate at the permanent,
permanent flip-flops
on Basilica itself.
So the difference, or
the main difference in
this case of
ethics, that the,
you know, the result
and the circuit in
the basics that is
permanently gone
into the silicon.
Yeah, worse than the FPGA,
the support is made of
either attributed by
connecting the numbers of
this conflict
were or blocks.
Programmable
interconnects, right?
So these are the
main differences
between the FPGA is at
the ACP decides here.
So yeah, here.
Afterward, nos abuse,
GPU, FPGA, and ethics.
With us, the most
commonly used
components for
the computing in
the emerging computing
our teachers
or the customized
architectures here.
Now we have an overview
about the large
enumeration of
the CPU or GPU,
FPGA, and A6,
you have intuitive
overview about
the TSI for this
architecture's here.
In addition, according
to the details of
the few Jersey and also
the performance is
measured between the CPUs,
GPUs, FPGAs, and
also the ethics.
Yeah, we can overstate
the advantages.
And also that these
are the manager of
this types of
computing compounds.
A CBO, GPU, FPGA,
A6 after we have
the comparison
between their design
optimization, right?
So for instance, you
know about CPUs have
the highest compute
adaptability
because they are
designed for
the general purpose
processing.
Well, they have the
data noise, the
throughput,
and the lowest
of paradise up
because they are not
adequately specific,
right?
So along this
way or this row,
from this ABO
design to the GPO,
to the FPGA, and now
to the A6, right?
You know that
you can observe
that there is a
higher parallelize
them and also higher
in throughput that
can be achieved.
Cpu, gpu, FPGA to Isaac.
Yeah, actually, with a
high power efficiency.
So they have
different features
and different
performance here in,
in, including the
computer adaptability,
that computer power,
the latency and
the throughput,
and how they can
deal with or
optimize the
parallelism in a HA,
is the power efficiency in
this for camera of
computing our
teachers here.
So, yeah,
with the technology
development
as shown in the
comparison here,
actually the increasing
emerging
applications also,
why did you so
today among or a
AI accelerating platforms,
application-specific
integrated circuits.
A6 right at, composed of
the processing elements
connected in
different topologies.
Are these different
topologies can
definitely provide
the comparable
energy efficiency,
the optimizer latency or
other form factors
including the cost,
design flexibility,
that is
our complex,
the complexity.
So in addition, not with
a comparison there.
Yeah, as reported
by the top table.
A6.
This kind of architecture
design about the
A6 are becoming
more and more popular for
the implementation of
the AI applications.
Yeah, definitely
then the FPGA,
the GPU, and also
the CPUs today.
So we go also
observe formed
a few words that
the ethics,
Actually it is
going to dominate
the market as predicted
in this figure,
especially with
the increasing
applications for
the AI or machine
learning tasks.
So this is B
caught that A6 has
some major advantages in
the Including the dark,
energy efficiency and also
the latency and airy
for their
architecture design.
So these are the
benefits for the,
all the advantages for the
Arab than the
traditional FPGAs,
GPUs and also the CPUs.
So yeah, we'll note the
separate components,
including the FPGA, GPU or
CPU and also the
ethics lecture.
We are going to know how
we can integrate it.
Some of them or
part of them,
or all of them
together to design
a heterogeneous
computing teacher or
heterogeneous medical
pamphlets to benefit.
There are advantages
reservoir
for different
components here.
So in addition to
the pure design of,
of the bony those
CPUs or GPUs,
or if G or the A6
accurate than nozzle way.
It is the proper
way or why did they
used a way for computing
architecture design?
Yeah, that is to explore
the heterogeneous
Monaco platforms.
So for
the heterogeneous
multiple platforms here,
first actually, we need to
know what is the
heterogeneous computing.
Yeah, the heterogeneous
computing means all.
It refers to the
system that can use
more than one can
of the processor
or one can off
the courses.
So this distance,
gang performance or
energy efficiency,
not just a, by
any distinct type
of the processors.
Next, opposing views,
the pure suit GPUs.
Fpgas, all only
the basics.
But instead of that,
they are using their
design architecture by
adding that these
thymine or
co-processors senior,
but it brought ring
specialized
processing capability
to handle that
particular tasks.
So yeah, you will.
The heterogeneity that is,
in the context
of the computing
refer to different
instruction set
architectures.
Where you know that
the main processor has
one instruction set
architecture and
other processors
in the system can
have another.
Man.
He's a very different
architecture.
So well, there are
other types of
heterogeneity or with
the same instruction
set architecture.
For example, as we
mentioned before and
also showing here.
This film were showed
that you can see
that the big layer
architecture,
that is an
exception where,
you know the
instruction set
architectures of the
course are the same.
But in this heterogeneous
architecture,
yeah, it is a heterogeneous
architecture.
The heterogeneity
in this architecture
refers to
the speed of the different
microarchitectures
of the semi-structured
data picture.
Therefore, this can
make it more like
a symmetric
multiprocessing SMP.
So that danger here
means not to the.
Different instruction
set architectures.
And it refers to
the different beta for
the different
microarchitectures,
ways, the same instruction
set architecture.
So as long does
manner heterogeneous
architecture.
Actually the big
layer architecture is
so heterogeneous
computing architecture
develop emitted by the,
by the ARM Holdings
right eye,
a combo covering the
relatively back
receiving and
a slower processor cores.
Yeah, with the relatively
more powerful in a
more hungry course,
we call it the
big course here.
And otherwise the
nato course, right?
So typically only one side
or the other will be
active air want tsunamis,
only the big core to
every part on for
the applications.
Or there will be off at
the nato course
wherever your part
on for those specific
applications,
if may not have
the time to demands
on the performance, right?
So yeah, but all
this big course
in later course have
access to the same
mammary regions.
So the workload,
the Canvas
web that between
the course,
a little course of a fly.
That means the controller
or the management.
Manager can change
the workloads
or swap them
between the course,
nato course, to do
the resource
allocation or two,
actually, I
will quote that
to do the scheduling.
The the intention is
to create a
multi-core processor.
Just a better, yeah,
actually dynamically to do
the computation and to
satisfy the
computing needs.
And they can use
miss poorer than
the COGS low because
the big quarter
and course,
nato course have
different performance
yet also the power
consumption,
the ADS consumption here.
So they will be much
more energy efficient.
So that is to say that,
Yeah, Does the
peritoneum or
the management of the
big later course,
a miscarriage or
genius architecture
actually is 2,
10 net the processor
according to
a job in order
to minimize the
power consumption.
So the arms in marketing
mature RNA primase
up to like 70 for
a person living in
the power usage for
some activities
in average.
So that is a
huge improvement
in the power efficiency.
So most commonly,
you know,
there aren't big pictures.
Actually. They
are used for
eight multiprocessor
system on chip.
Not I will know it as
the MPI SOC write
for this course are
located on chip and
they have the same memory.
They can swap the
workloads between
EHRs are for the better
or controller, right?
So this one can
octahedral genius
architecture shown here.
Yeah.
And Mazur heterogeneous
medical platforms.
Now we need to refer to as
the IBM cell
broadband engine,
that is B architecture.
This is another title of
the hydrogens are
teacher to sign.
And one of the
famous one that
has the performance and
also for energy
efficiency.
So the cell
broadband anions
CBE here from IBM,
that is the power
octahedral based on
microprocessor development
for the high workload
for the multimedia
based computing.
And the cell processor was
designed by STI etch,
that is a Plattner amongst
thorny Toshiba
and also IBM.
Although IBM remains
the piggyback off
this project that
you designed,
that multiprocessor,
Pavlov.
So this is filled with
a massive floating
point operations
in men and the
original process
and develop the
ways the lack
the power outage your
core surrounded by eight.
Assume here.
The eight is synergistic
processors here.
Although the
cell processor
has proven computing
potential,
yeah, it is widely
regarded as
the challenge of
programming environment.
So the snail broadband
aging teacher a year was
designed for the
distributed processing
is in us.
So that way you're fast
said a family all
of the processes
with a range of
the available course and
also the memory
configuration.
So this
architecture or no,
the sale family or dress,
different domains
where they
can use the same basic
hardware design.
So basically the
snail is system
has to components here.
The first one
that they hatha,
have a one or
more PowerPC,
a process of elements.
This can handle the
system management.
And a one or more system.
Strategist David
process are
adamant that it can
perform that data,
have a parallel
computing here.
So another coordinate
data sale V0
system also has
one inherent
into rot contour
and a one element
interconnect
reparse BIP here.
Yeah, these are used for
connecting the units.
We're using the processor.
So they seized the
design or the flow of
the IBM step broadband
a new architecture
with the course here.
And yet there's other
components here too,
just to connecting at
the process of
elements here.
So so i then these are
the basic components
computing
compounds to add also
that your famers,
heterogeneous molecule
pamphlets from
the arm and also
from A-B IBM, right?
So yeah, this to
stagger or PET,
da, da, da, da, da,
da represent,
representation for
the heterogeneous
architecture design.
And in the next
class we will show
more general heterogeneous
computing systems.
Not specific for
the course or
the update later
architectures
for or from idea.
But there are other
general heterogeneous
computing system
with a general components,
the memory design
and the connection.
So in the next class
we will show you more
about this kind of
general heterogeneous
architectures.
So thank you so
much for attending
this class and these are
the content for
this class.
Though.
Then go everyone and
hope you can enjoy
the holiday with you,
your family, for
Thanksgiving.
So things have
thank you so much.